A Guide to St. Thomas Aquinas Church Blueprints & Specifications, 1986-1996
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
St. Thomas Aquinas Church Blueprints & Specifications 1986-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11255
96 drawings in 3 oversize folders, ca. 245 items (2 Hollinger Boxes, ca. 4.5 linear shelf feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library on September 9, 1996, by Fr. Stephen Fitzhenry OP, St. Thomas Aquinas Church Parish House, Charlottesville, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of papers and architectural blueprints, 1986-1996, concerning the construction of the new St. Thomas Aquinas Church in Charlottesville, Virginia, by the architectural firm of VMDO Architects; Southern Air, Inc., MEP Contractor; Fox Applegate, Structural Engineers; and McKee/Carson, Civil Engineers. These papers include correspondence, diagrams and artwork for stained-glass window designs, a proposal for a capital fund campaign, specification manuals, and blueprints for the new church, parking lot, and pew arrangements.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically and numerically by series.
Contents List
- Correspondence re the Building and Renovation of Saint Thomas Church 1986-1996, n.d., 4 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Balzer and Associates 1990 & 1993 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with the University of Virginia re the Parking Lot 1992 & 1994 (Box 1)
- Diagrams & Artwork ca. 1994 (Box 1)
- "Proposal to Design and to Conduct a Capital Fund Campaign for a New Church" by The Martin J. Moran Company ca. 1990 (Box 1)
- Detail Manual 1994 Sep 20, Bound Volumes (2 copies) (Box 1)
- Detail Manual 1994 Sep 20, Bound Volume (Box 2)
- Project Manual 1994 Sep 20, Bound Volume (3 copies) (Box 2)
- Oversize Architectural Drawings (Folder 1-3)
  - Cover Sheet (Folder 1)
    - Design Development Cover Sheet 1993 Nov 3 (Folder 1)
  - Civil (Folder 1)
    - C-1 Site Plan 1993 Oct 19 (Folder 1)
    - C-2 Erosion & Sediment Control Plan, Details and Storm Sewer Profile 1993 Oct 19 (Folder 1)
  - Architectural (Folder 1)
    - A1.1 Ground & First Floor Plans 1993 Nov 2 (Folder 1)
    - A2.1 Exterior Elevations 1993 Oct 25 (Folder 1)
    - A3.1 Building Sections 1993 Nov 2 (Folder 1)
    - A3.2 Building Sections 1993 Nov 3 (Folder 1)
    - A3.3 Building Sections 1993 Nov 3 (Folder 1)
    - A7.1 Reflected Ceiling Plans 1993 Nov 3 (Folder 1)
  - Cover Sheet (Folder 1)
    - St. Thomas Aquinas New Church 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
  - Civil (Folder 1)
    - C-1 Site Plan 1993 Oct 19 (Folder 1)
    - C-2 Erosion & Sediment Control Plan, Details and Storm Sewer Profile 1993 Oct 1993 (Folder 1)
  - Architectural (Folder 1)
    - A1.1 Ground Floor Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A1.2 First Floor Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A1.3 Roof Plan & Partial Plans 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A2.1 Exterior Elevations 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A3.1 Building Sections & Partial Elevations 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A3.2 Building Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A3.3 Building Sections & Interior Elevations 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A5.1 Door Schedule & Finish Schedule 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - A7.1 Reflected Ceiling Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - FP 1.0 Fire Protection Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
  - Structural (Folder 1)
    - S-1 Foundation Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - S-2 First Floor Framing Plan & Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - S-3 Roof Framing Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - S-4 Foundations Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - S-5 Floor Framing Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - S-6 Roof Framing Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
    - S-7 Roof Framing Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 1)
  - Cover Sheet (Folder 2)
    - St. Thomas Aquinas New Church 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
  - Civil (Folder 2)
    - C-1 Site Plan 1993 Oct 19 (Folder 2)
    - C-2 Erosion & Sediment Control Plan, Details and Storm Sewer Profile 1993 Oct 19 (Folder 2)
  - Architectural (Folder 2)
    - A1.1 Ground Floor Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A1.2 First Floor Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A1.3 Roof Plan & Partial Plans 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A2.1 Exterior Elevations 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A3.1 Building Sections & Partial Elevations 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A3.2 Building Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A3.3 Building Sections & Interior Elevations 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A5.1 Door Schedule & Finish Schedule 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - A7.1 Reflected Ceiling Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - FP 1.0 Fire Protection Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
  - Structural (Folder 2)
    - S-1 Foundation Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - S-2 First Floor Framing Plan & Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - S-3 Roof Framing Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - S-4 Foundation Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - S-5 Floor Framing Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - S-6 Roof Framing sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - S-7 Roof Framing Sections 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
  - Plumbing (Folder 2)
    - P-1 Ground Floor Plumbing Plan 1994 Sep 16 (Folder 2)
    - P-2 First Floor Plumbing Plan 1994 Sep 15 (Folder 2)
    - P-3 1/4" Scale Toilet Plans 1994 Sep 16 (Folder 2)
    - P-4 Storm Drainage Plan 1994 Sep 15 (Folder 2)
  - Mechanical (Folder 2)
    - H-1 Ground Floor HVAC Plan 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
    - H-2 First Floor HVAC Plan 1994 Sep 16 (Folder 2)
    - H-3 HVAC Schedules 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
  - Electrical (Folder 2)
    - El-1 Ground Floor Lighting Plan 1994 Sep 19 (Folder 2)
    - EL-2 First Floor Lighting Plan 1994 Sep 19 (Folder 2)
    - EP-1 Ground Floor Power Plan 1994 Sep 19 (Folder 2)
    - EP-2 First Floor Power Plan 1994 Sep 19 (Folder 2)
    - ER-1 Sound System/Fire Alarm/Power Riser Diagrams 1994 Sep 19 (Folder 2)
    - ES-1 Dimmer System Riser Diagrams & Schedules 1994 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
  - T-1 Title Sheet for Alderman Road Parking/Storm Water Management Facility 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-1 Site Plan 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-2 Erosion & Sediment Control Plan 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-3 Erosion & Sediment Control Plan 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-4 Profiles & Details 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-5 Storm Water Management Details 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-6 Details & Notes 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-7 Final Site Plan 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - C-8 Final Site Plan 1992 Aug 15 (Folder 3)
  - Mitered Pew Layout 1994 Dec 12 (Folder 3)
  - Radius Pew Layout 1994 Dec 13, 2 sheets (Folder 3)
  - FF01 Floor Finish Plan 1996 Apr 1 (Folder 3)
  - Schematic Master Plan n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 3)
  - Schematic Floor Plans - Upper & Lower Levels n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 3)
  - New Facilities Study, including Schematic Master Plan, Main Entrance, Entry View from Alderman Road, & Elevation View from Alderman Road n.d., 8 sheets (Folder 3)
  - A-1 Schematic Master Plan (For Review Only Not For Construction) n.d. (Folder 3)
  - A-2 Main Level Plan (For Review Only Not For Construction) n.d. (Folder 3)
  - A-3 Lower Level Plan (For Review Only Not For Construction) n.d. (Folder 3)
  - A-4 Rear, Side & Front Elevations (For Review Only Not For Construction) n.d. (Folder 3)
  - A Proposal for Architectural & Engineering Services for St. Thomas Church n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Colored Rendition of the St. Thomas Aquinas New Facilities Study, including Main Entrance, Entry View from Alderman Road, Elevation View from Alderman Road, and Schematic Master Plan n.d. (Folder 3)